<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kubernetes on Ye Zheng&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://www.yezheng.pro/tags/kubernetes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Kubernetes on Ye Zheng&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.yezheng.pro/tags/kubernetes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hands-On Docker for Microservices with Python</title>
      <link>http://www.yezheng.pro/post/specialization/web-application/back-end/hands-on_docker_for_microservices_with_python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.yezheng.pro/post/specialization/web-application/back-end/hands-on_docker_for_microservices_with_python/</guid>
      <description>Preface For the technical aspects, we will use well-tailored tools, including the following: Python, to implement RESTful web services Git source control, to track the changes in an implementation, and GitHub, to share those changes Docker containers, to standardize the operation of each of the microservices Kubernetes, to coordinate the execution of multiple services Cloud services, such as Travis CI or AWS, to leverage existing commercial solutions to problems We</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing Lightweight Microservices Using Kubernetes</title>
      <link>http://www.yezheng.pro/post/specialization/web-application/spring/microservice-with-kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.yezheng.pro/post/specialization/web-application/spring/microservice-with-kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>Introduction to Kubernetes Deploying Our Microservices in Kubernetes Implementing Kubernetes Features as an Alternative Using a Service Mesh to Improve Observability and Management Centralized Logging with the EFK Stack Monitoring Microservices </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes Basics</title>
      <link>http://www.yezheng.pro/post/specialization/devops/kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.yezheng.pro/post/specialization/devops/kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>Using Minikube to Create a Cluster Kubernetes Clusters Kubernetes coordinates a highly available cluster of computers that are connected to work as a single unit.
applications need to be packaged in a way that decouples them from individual hosts: they need to be containerized.
Kubernetes automates the distribution and scheduling of application containers across a cluster in a more efficient way.
A Kubernetes cluster consists of two types of resources:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
