<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>linux on Ye Zheng&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://csyezheng.github.io/tags/linux/</link>
    <description>Recent content in linux on Ye Zheng&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://csyezheng.github.io/tags/linux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Post-installation for archlinux</title>
      <link>http://csyezheng.github.io/post/any-path/post-installation-for-archlinux/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csyezheng.github.io/post/any-path/post-installation-for-archlinux/</guid>
      <description>Reboot into the new system Set the keyboard layout and Console fonts If you have the 4K display, console fonts will be extremely small.
$ setfont sun12x22 Connect to the internet nmcli device wifi list nmcli device wifi connect TP-LINK_GZS password a3628436 ping baidu.com Unofficial user repositories sudo vim /etc/pacman.conf [archlinuxcn] Server = https://mirrors.tuna.tsinghua.edu.cn/archlinuxcn/$arch Adding unofficial keys
sudo pacman -Syy &amp;amp;&amp;amp; sudo pacman -S archlinuxcn-keyring Fonts sudo pacman -S ttc-iosevka-slab noto-fonts noto-fonts-cjk noto-fonts-emoji tf-latinmodern-math ttf-inconsolata Graphical user interface Display server sudo pacman -S xorg-server xorg-xrdb xorg-xbacklight xorg-xrdb is using to loading a user-level configuration dotfile, typically located at ~/.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup a Archlinux / Windows10 dual booting system</title>
      <link>http://csyezheng.github.io/post/any-path/setup-a-archlinux-windows10-dual-booting-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csyezheng.github.io/post/any-path/setup-a-archlinux-windows10-dual-booting-system/</guid>
      <description>Before   Check the hardware, three disks on my Lenovo ThinkPad P50
  Samsung SSD 970 EVO Plus 250GB for installing windows
  Samsung SSD 960 EVO 250GB for installling archlinux
  WDC WD5000LPLX-0 HHD 500GB for data storage
    Disable Windows Fast Startup if start from windows
  Disable UEFI Secure Boot. (Arch Linux install media does not support Secure Boot.)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bash Reference Manual</title>
      <link>http://csyezheng.github.io/post/any-path/bash/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csyezheng.github.io/post/any-path/bash/</guid>
      <description>Bash Reference Manual Basic Shell Features Shell Syntax Shell Operation Quoting Escape Character A non-quoted backslash \ is the Bash escape character. It preserves the literal value of the next character that follows, with the exception of \newline.
Single Quotes Enclosing characters in single quotes (&#39;) preserves the literal value of each character within the quotes. A single quote may not occur between single quotes, even when preceded by a backslash.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UNIX / Linux Short Remedial</title>
      <link>http://csyezheng.github.io/post/any-path/unix-short-remedial/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csyezheng.github.io/post/any-path/unix-short-remedial/</guid>
      <description>Shell and Basic Commands A shell is a program1 that inputs Unix commands from the keyboard and relays them to the Unix system for execution. Shells typically include various shortcuts for users to use in stating their commands, and also a programming feature, in which users can make programs out of sets of their commands.
There are many different shells available for Unix systems. Here we focus on two of the most popular ones, tcsh and bash.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
