<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hackintosh on Ye Zheng&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://www.yezheng.pro/tags/hackintosh/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hackintosh on Ye Zheng&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://www.yezheng.pro/tags/hackintosh/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hackintosh Install Full Guide</title>
      <link>http://www.yezheng.pro/post/any-path/hackintosh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.yezheng.pro/post/any-path/hackintosh/</guid>
      <description>Step 0: Preparation You will need a computer running macOS already to follow this guide. If you do not have a Mac you will need to spend some time setting up a virtual machine on your Windows/Linux PC first.
 vmware workstation vmware macos unlocker workstation unlocker: https://github.com/paolo-projects/unlocker.git Download macOS Catalina Image file for VMWare  Step 1: Download macOS Catalina Download Catalina 10.15 from the Mac App Store
For machines that need a specific OS release or can&amp;rsquo;t download from the App Store, you can use the gibMacOS utility.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>hackintosh</title>
      <link>http://www.yezheng.pro/post/other/hackintosh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.yezheng.pro/post/other/hackintosh/</guid>
      <description>Step 1: Download – Get a copy of macOS Catalina Download Catalina 10.15 from the Mac App Store
download it through a third party source such as gibMacOS.
Step 2: Installer – Create the macOS Catalina flash drive   Formatting the USB Drive  Click Erase Set the following settings:  Name: Hackintosher Format: Mac OS Extended (Journaled) Scheme: GUID Partition Map   Click Erase    Transferring the Catalina Installer  balena-etcher    Step 3: Catalina EFI Partition &amp;amp; Clover Files  Mount EFI Partition Delete the folder called EFI in the partition you mounted (If it exists) Download Hackintosher-Catalina-10.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
