<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>cloud-computing on Ye Zheng&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>http://csyezheng.github.io/categories/cloud-computing/</link>
    <description>Recent content in cloud-computing on Ye Zheng&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://csyezheng.github.io/categories/cloud-computing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Cloud Computing</title>
      <link>http://csyezheng.github.io/post/specialization/cloud-computing/15-319/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csyezheng.github.io/post/specialization/cloud-computing/15-319/</guid>
      <description>Introduction and Course Logistics Data Analytics Big Data Analytics Elasticity and Auto Scaling Containers and Kubernetes Serverless Computing and Functions-as-a-Service Flat Files and Databases &amp;amp; Team Project Social Network, Heterogenous Storage and DBaaS &amp;amp; Team Project Replication and Consistency and Team Project Phase 1 Team Project Phase 1 Iterative Batch Processing in Spark and Team Project Phase 2 Team Project Phase 2 and Live Test Machine Learning on the Cloud and Team Project Phase 3 Team Project Phase 3 and Live Test Stream Processing with Kafka &amp;amp; Samza Reference  https://www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to Cloud Infrastructure Technologies</title>
      <link>http://csyezheng.github.io/post/specialization/cloud-computing/infrastructure/introduction-to-cloud-infrastructure-technologies/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://csyezheng.github.io/post/specialization/cloud-computing/infrastructure/introduction-to-cloud-infrastructure-technologies/</guid>
      <description>Chapter 1. Virtualization Introduction and Learning Objectives Introduction to Cloud Computing and Technologies Historically, the word cloud was used as a metaphor for Internet. Later on, it was used to depict the Internet in computer network diagrams. To find out more about the origin of the cloud, you can take a look at the details provided on Wikipedia.
Cloud computing can be referred as the allocation of resources on the cloud.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
